# Reshav Abraham

# Full Stack ML Engineer

#### about me

I am a passionate software engineer interested in Full stack development and machine learning. I have experience building backend API's and Frontends. I also have experience in training and serving machine learning models.



☑reshavabraham@gmail.com

Ohttps://github.com/reshav-abraham

inwww.linkedin.com/in/reshav-abraham-ab8016a5

★160 Vroom Street, Jersey City

# Work Experience

### **NImatics**

#### **NLP Engineer**

New York, NY — October 2019 - April 2021

- \* Improved text indexing from PDF documents to enhance search retrieval quality.
- \* Designed back-end APIs with Python and Swagger.
- \* Built out front-end features with React and ANT design.
- \* Lead on-prem installation for clients and deploying on restrictive environments.
- \* Maintained and debugged CI/CD pipelines, with Docker and Kubernetes.
- \* Designed and Implemented a Search Flagging/Approval System to track dips and improvements in search quality.

### Dell EMC

#### **Software Intern**

Charlotte, NC — May 2017 — August 2017

\* Optimized memory usage for enterprise data pipelining software by modeling a regression on real-time memory consumption data using Apache Spark.

## Certificates

#### Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning

Stanford University, CS224N

October 2020 — December 2020

- $\ast$  Developed a Neural Machine Language Translation model in PyTorch.
- $\ast\,$  Implemented encoder and decoder networks using LSTM and CNN layers for processing out-of-vocabulary words.

# **Projects**

#### **Human Voice Detection**

- \* Developed a neural network architecture using CNN and linear layers for processing audio signals to identify human voices.
- \* Developed a script for scraping audio from YouTube playlists.
- \* Utilized MFCC and other signal processing techniques to prepare data.

# Technical Skills

Languages Python, JavaScript, Bash, C++, Java

Frameworks PyTorch, Tensorflow, Swagger, React

DevOps Docker, Kubernetes, Nginx

Coud GCP, Azure

Databases MongoDB, Postgress, Redis

Markup LATEX, HTML, CSS, Markdown

Misc Git, Linux, Clubhouse, Jira, Jupyter

### Education

# B.S Computer Engineering Purdue University

West Lafayette, Indiana 2014 - 2018

#### Multi-core Processor System Verilog

\* Implemented a synthesizable multi-core processor for processing MIPS assembly language in SystemVerilog.

#### Automated Nerf-Gun Turret

- \* Engineered a turret gun that detects human targets and shoots Nerf darts at them.
- $\ast$  Implemented human-target detection with Mobile NetSSD and OpenCV.

#### Interests

- \* Soccer
- \* Guitar
- \* Chess